<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aaron Swartz on Nadeem Hilal</title>
    <link>https://nhwaani.github.io/authors/aaron-swartz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aaron Swartz on Nadeem Hilal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 16:15:18 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nhwaani.github.io/authors/aaron-swartz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Critical Ingredient to Become a Genius</title>
      <link>https://nhwaani.github.io/archives/2020/04/critical-ingredient-to-become-a-genius/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 16:15:18 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nhwaani.github.io/archives/2020/04/critical-ingredient-to-become-a-genius/</guid>
      <description>Everyone knows that to do great work you need both natural ability and determination. But there’s a third ingredient that’s not as well understood: an obsessive interest in a particular topic
To explain this point I need to burn my reputation with some group of people, and I’m going to choose bus ticket collectors. There are people who collect old bus tickets. Like many collectors, they have an obsessive interest in the minutiae of what they collect.
They can keep track of distinctions between different types of bus tickets that would be hard for the rest of us to remember. Because we don’t care enough. What’s the point of spending so much time thinking about old bus tickets?
Which leads us to the second feature of this kind of obsession: there is no point. A bus ticket collector’s love is disinterested. They’re not doing it to impress us or to make themselves rich, but for its own sake
When you look at the lives of people who’ve done great work, you see a consistent pattern. They often begin with a bus ticket collector’s obsessive interest in something that would have seemed pointless to most of their contemporaries. One of the most striking features of Darwin’s book about his voyage on the Beagle is the sheer depth of his interest in natural history.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
