<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on Nadeem Hilal</title>
    <link>https://nhwaani.github.io/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on Nadeem Hilal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:14:21 +0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nhwaani.github.io/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Write Code That Is Easy to Delete</title>
      <link>https://nhwaani.github.io/posts/2020/04/write-code-that-is-easy-to-delete/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:14:21 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nhwaani.github.io/posts/2020/04/write-code-that-is-easy-to-delete/</guid>
      <description>“Every line of code is written without reason, maintained out of weakness, and deleted by chance” Jean-Paul Sartre’s Programming in ANSI C.
 Every line of code written comes at a price: maintenance. To avoid paying for a lot of code, we build reusable software. The problem with code re-use is that it gets in the way of changing your mind later on.
The more consumers of an API you have, the more code you must rewrite to introduce changes. Similarly, the more you rely on an third-party api, the more you suffer when it changes. Managing how the code fits together, or which parts depend on others, is a significant problem in large scale systems, and it gets harder as your project grows older.
 My point today is that, if we wish to count lines of code, we should not regard them as “lines produced” but as “lines spent” EWD 1036
 If we see ‘lines of code’ as ‘lines spent’, then when we delete lines of code, we are lowering the cost of maintenance. Instead of building re-usable software, we should try to build disposable software.
I don’t need to tell you that deleting code is more fun than writing it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>