<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>book-reviews on Nadeem Hilal</title>
    <link>https://nhwaani.github.io/tags/book-reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in book-reviews on Nadeem Hilal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:48:21 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nhwaani.github.io/tags/book-reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Review the Pragmatic Programmer</title>
      <link>https://nhwaani.github.io/posts/2020/06/review-the-pragmatic-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:48:21 +0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nhwaani.github.io/posts/2020/06/review-the-pragmatic-programmer/</guid>
      <description>Today i decided to add my review about one of the best books among the software engineers, its a must to have in your bookshelf. The book was written by Dave Thomas and Andy Hunt , and the motto of the book was
YOUR JOURNEY TO MASTERY. This book starts with simple yet profound message
 ITS YOUR LIFE
 It reminds us of our own power in our code-base, jobs , careers. Why this book is different then other books is that it understands what it means to be a programmer. As a relative newcommer, its easy to be overwhelmed not by the act of programming but the process of becoming a programmer.
There is an entire mindset shift that needs to happen &amp;ndash; c changed in the habbits, behaviours, and expectations. The book says that the process of becoming the better programmer does not just happen because
 you know how to code ; It must be met with intention and delibrate practice
 And believe me this book teach it best.
Just a quick reminder, i will be reviewing thier 20th Edition as it the updated edition that came out recently &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
